Finding Aid for John Harvey Kellogg Papers, 1832-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Lectures, Speeches, and Related Materials
  - 1923-1926, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - An Address to the Students of the School of Home Economics May 20, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture October 4, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Untitled broadcast address October 25, 1926 (Box 7)
  - 1927, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Take a Vacation undated (Box 7)
    - The Vital Overhead undated (Box 7)
    - The Early Beginnings January 13, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Pig and Long-Pig February 6, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Shoddy February 7, 1927 (Box 7)
    - The Successful Treatment of Colitis May 17, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Rational Physical Treatment of Gastric Hyperacidity June 9, 1927 (Box 7)
    - The Great Destroyer (alcohol) July 27, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Special Features of the Battle Creek Sanitarium Bill of Fare August 2, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Rational Physical Therapy September 12, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Diet of Finnish Athletes November 1927 (Box 7)
    - How to Make Battle Creek A Greater City December 5, 1927 (Box 7)
  - June-August 1928, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture June 4, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture July 30, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture August 13, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Why We Should Eat More Potatoes August 3, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Alcott's "Potato Gospel" August 10, 1928 (Box 7)
    - The American Potato Might Have Won the Marathon August 10, 1928 (Box 7)
  - October-December 1928, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Eating for Health and Efficiency October 18, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture October 28, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Institutional Care of Chronic Invalids October 31, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture November 4, 1928 (Box 7)
    - The Sinusoidal Electric Bath November 10, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Practical Results in the Institutional Treatment of Twenty-Five Hundred Cases of High Blood Pressure November 30, 1928 (Box 7)
  - 1929, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Safety Margin and Tobacco (Box 7)
    - Memoranda about Tea and Coffee (Box 7)
    - A New and Successful Method of Treatment for the Opium Habit and Other Forms of Drug Addiction (Box 7)
    - The Battle Creek Sanitarium Fire (Box 7)
    - The Rebuilding of the Battle Creek Sanitarium (2 versions) (Box 7)
    - Battle Creek College (Box 7)
    - How the Sick Are Healed (Box 7)
  - April-August 1929, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Correlated Physiotherapy April 29, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture May 20, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture June 10, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture (portion) July 15, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Papaya July 30, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Hygos; The New Health Gum August 31, 1929 (Box 7)
  - 1930, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture June 2, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Does Prohibition Make Scoff-Laws? June 6, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture June 29, 1930 (Box 7)
    - What Makes a Man Tired? July 1930 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture July 7, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture July 14, 1930 (Box 7)
    - The Battle Creek Sanitarium Sends a Skilled Dietitian to Labrador July 23, 1930 (Box 7)
    - The Reason Why July 28, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Soybeans as Human Food September 11, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture September 29, 1930 (Box 7)
  - 1931-1933, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - An Address to Members of the Miami Three Score and Ten Club March 17, 1931 (Box 7)
    - A Tempest in an Oyster Pot April 12, 1931 (Box 7)
    - Oriental Sampsons June 23, 1931 (Box 7)
    - The Practical Results of Biologic Living July 5, 1931 (Box 7)
    - Battle Creek Ideals October 6, 1931 (Box 7)
    - That Most Useful Remedy, the Enema-Its Use and Abuse October 10, 1931 (Box 7)
    - To Pasteurize or Not to Pasteurize October 10, 1931 (Box 7)
    - New discoveries about Changing the Intestinal Flora December 10, 1931 (Box 7)
    - Engine Trouble; What May a Hypertension Patient do to better his condition and prolong his life? January 27, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Walking Back March 8, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Bran Does Not Cause, but Heals, Castric Ulcer in Rats March 8, 1932 (Box 7)
    - The Successful Treatment of Colitis March 15, 1932 (Box 7)
    - The Aims and Ideals of Battle Creek College March 31, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Arteriosclerosis April 11, 1932 (Box 7)
    - The Eskimos Not Exclusive Meat Eaters May 2, 1932 (Box 7)
    - The Banana Cure for Celiac Disease August 31, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Orange Juice versus "Flu" February 9, 1933 (Box 7)
    - Untitled lecture regarding visit of Surgeon General O'Reilly March 1933 (Box 7)
    - How Much Does Hypertension Influence Life Extension or Expectation? September 13, 1933 (Box 7)
  - 1934-1935, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Battle Creek System of Physical Education June 6, 1934 (Box 7)
    - Health Demands December 18, 1934 (Box 7)
    - Notes from a lecture March 10, 1935 (Box 7)
    - Nature's Method of Combating Putrefaction in the Colon by Changing the Intestinal Flora April 26, 1935 (Box 7)
    - To Suppress Intestinal Putrefaction in the Colon by Changing the Intestinal Flora April 26, 1935 (Box 7)
    - An Address to the Students of Home Economics of Battle Creek College June 6, 1935 (Box 7)
    - The World Famine October 16, 1935 (Box 7)
    - Improved Apparatus for Irrigating and Flushing the Colon November 2, 1935 (Box 7)
    - A Worm that Borrows Weapons for Defense December 5, 1935, December 6, 1935 (2 versions) (Box 7)
    - The Aristocracy of Health Based on Biologic Living circa 1935 (Box 7)
  - 1936-1937, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - A Positive and Practical Method of Changing the Intestinal Flora Employing a New and More Potent Culture of Lactobacillus Bifidus-Acidophilus, January 30, 1936. (Box 7)
    - An Early Experience in Changing the Intestinal Flora July 2, 1936 (Box 7)
    - A Lecture in the Old Sanitarium Lobby July 6, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Lecture in the Sanitarium Dining Room August 3, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Change of the Intestinal Flora August 16, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Untitled talk October 21, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Alcohol Compared with Florida Sunshine February 24, 1937 (Box 7)
    - A Rational System of Physical Training Based on Strength Tests of all Important Groups of Muscles March 7, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Vitamin A April 10, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Human Life Extended Seven Years by Vitamins September 15, 1937 (Box 7)
    - A Chat About Health Foods October 4, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Special Health Values of the Soybean October 5, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Special Features of the Battle Creek Sanitarium: Bill of Fare October 17, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Rheumatic Fibrositis November 11, 1937 (Box 7)
    - What Physiotherapy Can Do for Chronic Invalids December 17, 1937 (Box 7)
  - 1938, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Normal Colon Habits January 7, 1938 (Box 7)
    - The Case Against Meat Eating January 11, 1938 (Box 7)
    - The Ideal Food Laxative January 18, 1938 (2 versions) (Box 7)
    - Direction for Using LD-Lax January 21, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Colon Poisons January 30, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Lecture to Patients of the Miami-Battle Creek in the Sanitarium January 31, 1938 (Box 7)
    - The Constipation Problem Solved February 17, 1938 (Box 7)
    - A Master Germ March 17, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Lecture to Patients of the Miami-Battle Creek in the Sanitarium March 27, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Lecture to Patients of the Miami-Battle Creek in the Sanitarium April 17, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Untitled autobiographical statement October 21, 1938 (Box 7)
  - 1939-1940, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - A Summer Message for Battle Creek July 10, 1939 (Box 7)
    - Vital Energy December 27, 1939 (Box 7)
    - The Mission of Food Health is to Help Save Civilization through Race Betterment and Biologic Living January 23, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Is B. Coli a Protective Organism or a Menace? February 29, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Short Talks About Health March 10, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Soy Acidophilus Concentrate March 21, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Who and What Are Faddists? April 20, 1940 (Box 7)
    - B. Coli: A Parasite and Not a Desirable Resident of the Colon April 25, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Old Age is a Disease May 3, 1940 (Box 7)
    - The Alcohol of Beer and Wine as Damaging as That of Rum and Whiskey May 27, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Philosophy of Life June 5, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Early History of the Oxygen Tent July 28, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Untitled typescript of article on sugar July 1, 1940 (Box 7)
    - The War Spirit July 9, 1940 (Box 7)
  - 1941-1942, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Nature a False God February 17, 1941 (Box 7)
    - My Search for Health January 16, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Untitled essay re colon March 14, 1942 (Box 7)
    - The New Sugar; B-Lac or Beta Lactose April 1, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Question Box Lecture July 27, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Vitamins October 1942 (Box 7)
    - Lecture in the Sanitarium Lobby December 26, 1942 (Box 7)
  - 1943, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Sewage in the Colon January 13, 1943 (Box 7)
    - Drink More Water February 4, 1943 (Box 7)
    - Physiologic Prayer April 22, 1943 (Box 7)
    - The Gorilla's Secret September 15, 1943, November 1943 (2 pts.) (Box 7)
- Notes and Articles
  The Notes and Articles series (4 linear feet; between 1890 and 1943) contains miscellaneous original and collected material, not always clearly identified, one portion of which is grouped together alphabetically by broad topic while another portion is arranged chronologically.
  - Alcohol, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
  - Arthritis, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
  - Battle Creek Sanitarium, 3 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
  - Biologic Living, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
  - Catalog of Kellogg Library, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
  - Circulatory System, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Colon and Gastro-Intestinal Tract, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Diet for Special Age Groups and Special Cases, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Diet (general), 3 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Dietetics, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Diseases, diagnosis, and treatment, 10 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Dress, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 8)
  - Education, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Electric Current for Medical Use, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Exercise, 4 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Food, 5 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Health, 4 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Health Compendium (bound manuscript), .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - History and Health, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Hydrotherapy, 3 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Longevity, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 9)
  - Manual Swedish Movements, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Meats, Tobacco, Tea, and Coffee, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - "Natural Living", .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Physiology, 5 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Politics, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Question Box Lectures, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Race Betterment and Eugenics, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Thermotherapy, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Women's Work/Housekeeping, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
  - Memoranda [dated files]
    - 1876-1899, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
    - 1900-1907, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 10)
    - 1910-1919, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
    - 1920-1929, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
    - 1930-1939, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
    - 1940-1943, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
- Subject Files (primarily medical missionary materials)
  Subject Files (1.3 linear feet; between 1885 and 1920) is arranged alphabetically by topic and relates primarily to Kellogg's interest in medical missionaries.
  - American Medical Missionary College circa 1901-1907, 3 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
  - Battle Creek Sanitarium 1881-1944, undated, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 11)
  - Chicago Medical Missionary School (and Working Men's Home and Medical Mission) 1891-1907, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Chicago Medical Missions: Chapel Talk and Announcement 1897-1898, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Christian Help Bands circa 1895-1898, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - International Health Association 1894-1899, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - International Medical Alliance 1905-1907, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - International Medical Missionary and Benevolent Association (Seventh-Day Adventist) 1894-1907, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Interdenominational Medical Missionary Conference 1909, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Legal Papers and Patents 1896-1936, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Medical Faculty Meetings 1898-1900, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Medical Missionary
    - Board, 1895-1901 and undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
    - Proceedings of Medical Missionary Conference and Convention 1905, 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
    - General (Correspondence, resolutions, meeting minutes, etc.) 1895-1908, undated, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
    - Lectures 1893-1906, undated, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous and Fragments 1906-1908, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
    - Published Materials: news clippings, brochures, and 'The Medical Missionary' journal 1906-1909, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Mexican Medical Mission (Guadalajara) 1897-1918, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Michigan Sanitarium and Benevolent Association 1897-1899, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Sanitarium Training School for Missionary Nurses 1893-1907, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Sanitariums and "Medical Missions and Benevolent Associations" in the United States and Abroad 1893-1907, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Seventh Day Adventist Medical Missionary and Benevolent Association 1891-1897, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Soul (Nature of) 1892-1901, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous (conference programs, "A Chewing Song" dedicated to Horace Fletcher, materials related to Richard E. Byrd's second Antarctic expedition, etc.) 1884-1943, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 12)
- Clippings and Scrapbooks
  The Clippings/Scrapbooks (2 linear feet; 1878-1952) consists of clipping files arranged both chronologically and by topic, and scrapbooks arranged chronologically supplemented by volumes pertaining to specific topics.
  - Clippings
    - 1879-1952, 9 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      (Arranged chronologically)
    - circa 1890-1965
      - Arthritis, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Battle Creek College, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Battle Creek Sanitarium, 3 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Biologic Living, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Health Training, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Kellogg, John Harvey
        - Biographical, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
        - Theory and Writings, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Longevity, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Medical Missionaries, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Race Betterment, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Three Quarter Century Club, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 13)
  - Unbound Scrapbooks, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - 1878-1904, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - 1906-1929, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Bound Scrapbooks
    - Various Subjects (including Kellogg and his death) 1904-1944, Paper: 2 volumes; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 21)
    - Chronological, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
      - 1897-1898 (Box 14)
      - 1931-1938 (Box 14)
    - Hygienist Abroad circa 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
    - Lane, Sir Arbuthnot 1926, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
    - Temperance circa 1885, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
    - Women's Concerns and Housekeeping undated, Paper: 3 volumes; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
- Bound Manuscripts and Published Volumes
  Bound Manuscripts/Published Volumes (4.5 linear feet; approximately between 1869 and 1940) consists of various ledgers and daybooks, Kellogg's student notebooks, his professional notebooks, manuscripts of essays and other writings, and published works by Kellogg and others in the field of health and nutrition. The notebooks in particular manifests Kellogg's quick mind as student and as a doctor in search of the most recent trends in medicine and surgery. Not part of this Kellogg collection, but also available at the Bentley Historical Library, is a collection of Kellogg's published writings and the Good Health magazine.
  - Guestbooks and Registers 1926-1944, Paper: 8 volumes; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 14)
  - Various (primarily family materials): biographical materials, diaries, expense books, etc. circa 1885-1909, 7 volumes; Paper: 7 volumes; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
  - Ledgers/Daybooks
    - 1889-1891, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
    - 1894-1899, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
    - 1897-1900, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
    - 1913-1923, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
  - Index Rerum circa 1888-1896, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 15)
  - Notebooks (J. H. Kellogg)
    - Student 1869-1875, Paper: 26 notebooks in 2 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 16)
    - Professional
      - 1877-1919, Paper: 41 notebooks in 3 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 16)
      - 1920-1927, Paper: 11 notebooks in 1 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
  - Topical File of Works by Kellogg or Battle Creek Sanitarium Doctors circa 1890-1940
    - Diseases, diagnosis, and treatment, Paper: 2 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Food and Dietetics, Paper: 2 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - General, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Health and Medical Institutions, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Iron Ration, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
  - Manuscripts by J.H. Kellogg circa 1890-1925
    - Health Compendium, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Man the Masterpiece, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Nature's Remedies, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 17)
  - Manuscripts (non-Kellogg) (Box 18)
    - Various Authors (arranged alphabetically) circa 1885-1940, Paper: 11 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 18)
    - Van Noorden, Karl. Metabolism and Practical Medicine, circa 1907, Paper: 4 volumes in 2 folders; Digital: .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 18)
  - Publications (non-Kellogg) circa 1832-1940
    - Alcohol, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Colon and Gastro-Intestinal Tract, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Diet and Food, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Disease, Diagnosis, and Treatment, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - General Health, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Race Betterment/Eugenics, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
- Photographs
  The Photograph series (0.8 linear feet; between 1880s and 1940s) includes portraits and photos of John Harvey Kellogg with family and friends, other photos concerning the Battle Creek Sanitarium, its buildings and the activities that it administered, Kellogg's interest in a Chicago mission house, and Kellogg's travels. There are also family photos.
  - Portraits of John Harvey Kellogg circa 1880s-1943, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Informal photos of John Harvey Kellogg (alone) 1919-1943, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Informal photos of John Harvey Kellogg (with others) 1912-1943, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Christmas card photographs 1906-1939, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Interiors and exteriors of Battle Creek and New York homes 1894, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Kellogg Mrs. John Harvey (ne Ella Ervilla Eaton) circa 1900-1915, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Kellogg family undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Travels
    - Africa 1925-1926, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - California 1928, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Florida 1918-1919, 1929-1930, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Leysin, Switzerland (Dr. Rollier's clinic) undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Chicago Mission undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Chicago Slums undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Battle Creek Sanitarium (old) circa 1880s-1902, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Battle Creek Sanitarium (new)
    - Dedication Ceremonies 1903, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Buildings undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Interiors undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Laboratory Scenes undated, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Pavlov Physiological Institute undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Physical fitness program undated, 2 folders; .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Deer Park undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Various Sanitarium Events and Activities circa 1910-1943, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
    - Staff undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - American Medical Missionary College 1910, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Portraits and miscellaneous (non-John Harvey Kellogg) 1891-1904, undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 19)
  - Oversized Photos (mainly Battle Creek Sanitarium views and activities) undated, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 20)
  - Album (summer playground and nutrition program for children) 1926, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 20)
  - Oversize materials; contents described above (Box 21)
Related Material at the Bentley Historical Library
Published works of John Harvey Kellogg, including books, pamphlets, and periodicals. Includes the Good Health magazine.
Selective Index of Correspondents
Barron, Clarence Walker, 1855-1928.
May 11, 1926
Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957.
Aug. and Oct. 1939
Edison, Mary Stilwell.
Feb. 8, 1931
Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947.
Dec. 2, 1935
Ford, Clara Bryant, 1866-1950.
Feb. 20, 1932, Feb. 21, 1932, April 1, 1932, Dec. 2, 1937, Feb. 21, 1940
Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.
Feb. 21, 1932, April 3, 1937
LeHand, Margaret.
July 27, 1933
Liebold, Ernest G., 1884-
Jan. 13, 1925, May 1937
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860
Sept. 1, 1930, Feb. 22, 1936, June 27, 1936, July 2, 1936, Feb. 7, 1938, Feb. 11, 1938, Feb. 24, 1940, Feb. 19, 1943
Pavlov, Ivan Petrovich, 1849-1936.
Oct. 22, 1924, Sept. 18, 1935; copy and letter of Pavlov to Professor Boldyreff, Mar. 22, 1924
Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946.
Mar. 13, 1931, Oct. 31, 1931, May 27, 1932, June 7, 1932, June 17, 1932, Oct.-Dec. 1936
Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901.
Jan. 13, 1898
Plunckett, Horace.
1919, Dec. 21, 1921, 1922-1925, Sept. 1929-1930
Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960.
Oct.-Dec. 1922, July 23, 1929, Dec. 2, 1937, Jan-May 1935, Dec. 11, 1941
Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.
July 27, 1933
Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.
Feb. 7, 1936, May 17, 1936, June 21, 1936
Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.
Aug. 24, 1922, Sept. 1922
Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.
July 20, 1939, July 28, 1939, Aug. 3, 1939, Oct. 28, 1939, Dec. 6, 1939, Jan. 5, 1940
Tolstoy, Alexandra, 1884-1979.
Aug. 6, 1939
Tolstoy, Ilga.
March 26, 1924
Tolstoy, Leo, 1828-1910.
Nov. 16, 1907, Dec. 11, 1907
Van Shaick, Louis J.
May 13, 1931